Muhammad Fathir Irhas

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · BACKEND DEVELOPER

Jakarta - Tangerang

🛮 (+62) 812-2444-1284 | 🗷 fathir.irhas@outlook.com | 🏕 mfathirirhas.github.io | 🖫 mfathirirhas | 🗖 mfathirirhas

Summary_

Highly passionate and enthusiast Software Engineer mostly in backend development and little frontend stuffs. Always learning to improve skills and willing to share. Able to work independently and in team. Write good and testable code and refactor them if needed. Provide solutions and improvement if needed. Have experiences developing system and services.

Education

Telkom University

Bandung, Indonesia

 SARJANA KOMPUTER(S.KOM)
 2012 - 2016

• GPA: 3.34

Experience _____

Tokopedia Jakarta, Indonesia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Jun 2018 - Now

- Working in Fintech Team
- · Contribute in Saldo Tokopedia, Tokocash(before shutdown), Internal Tools, and some investment products
- · Create and develop system and services that do CRUD in either Postgre, MySQL, and/or Redis(cache)
- · Create and develop system and services that communicate each other synchronously using REST, gRPC, and GQL as API gateway
- · Create and develop system and services that communicate each other asynchronously using PubSub NSQ(MQ) and/or using cron
- Create and develop some frontend element of the product(Saldo Tokopedia)
- Add, Fix, Change, and Maintain services and features in Fintech products
- Provide solutions and improvement to products features and services
- Monitor services running(server log, datadog, prometheus/grafana)
- Execute tickets coming from users through ops team relating to issues in products
- Participate in daily and sprint
- Participate in team sharing session every 2 weeks
- · Collaborate with other team to provide interface and integration to/from Fintech's products/services and provide solutions

Anabatic Technologies

Serpong Tangerang, Indonesia

Jan 2018 - Jun 2018

- TECHNICAL CONSULTANT
- Monitor client's app runningSupport product development and customization

Emporia Digital Raya, Anabatic Technologies

Serpong Tangerang, Indonesia

Nov 2016 - Dec 2017

- **SOFTWARE ENGINEER(JUNIOR)** Work in Agile running sprint every 2 weeks.
- Maintain Main site.
- Develop UI components using HTML, CSS, Javascript, and JSP.
- Develop web services in form of REST APIs, firebase push notif, mail services, authentication for mobile apps using PHP, Java and MySQL.
- · Versioning and deployment.

Chevron Pacific Indonesia Duri Riau, Indonesia

ÎNTERNSHIP 2015

- Internship under UTC-POD Team in IT Departement.
- Create simple web app using C# ASP.Net to handle request for well surveys.

Skill

Main

GOLANG, JS, POSTGRE, MYSQL, REDIS, NSQ, API, REST, GRPC, GQL, TEST

Others:

C#, Python, Java, PHP(Laravel & Codeigniter), Wordpress, Excel



Informatics Lab, Telkom University

Bandung, Indonesia

2013 - 2015

PRACTICUM ASSISTANT

• Held and support main practicum

Software Engineering Lab, Telkom University

Bandung, Indonesia

LAB ASSISTANT

2015 - 2016 • Study and research group. Held and support some lab activities including tutoring, mentoring, sharing knowledge, workshop, movies, game, game development community indie game developer enthusiast and other activities.

Hackathon MDK 2.0 Bandung, Indonesia

CONTESTANT Oct 2015

- Participate in second Hackathon held by Telkom around Indonesia.
- Developed simple web services to be consumed by Android

Other_

Blog: https://mfathirirhas.github.io/blog More: https://mfathirirhas.github.io/resume Portfolio: https://mfathirirhas.github.io/portfolio